William Will' B. Ditto

28 Dellenbaugh Loop Etna, Ohio 43062 P. 740.705.1098 E. Will.Ditto@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Currently, I am serving in the role of Business Liaison and Senior IT Manager with the Ohio Department of Taxation's Information Services Division (ISD) due to my previous roles on IT projects within the Department. Previously, I served as the Administrator of the Excise and Energy Tax Division and have over seventeen (17) years of experience in state taxation. Adept in managing a large group of employees while ensuring the various competing priorities and responsibilities are always achieved. A proven critical thinker, extremely versatile, self-driven, and constantly motivated by the opportunity to make changes and decisions that positively impact morale, culture, and the overall organization.

CORE COMPETENCIES

LeadershipSQL DeveloperPython/DjangoProduct Owner (Agile)Microsoft Excel VBADatabase SupportAgile Project ManagementMicrosoft Access VBATableau Visualizations

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Ohio Department of Taxation - Columbus, Ohio - July 2019 to Present

Business Customer Liaison Information Services Division

Contributions:

- Responsible for managing Business Intelligence for the Department of Taxation; including Tableau, Oracle SQL Developer, and Alteryx.
- Solely learned and built Python Tkinter Application for the Human Resources Division.
- Lead the effort regarding the movement of existing applications from the Mainframe.
- Developed numerous Cognos Reports to facilitate the identification of revenue producing tax programs.
- Nominated to be a participant in the IT Strategy Team.

Ohio Department of Taxation - Columbus, Ohio - May 2013 to July 2019

Administrator

Excise & Energy Tax Division

Contributions:

- Responsible for administering over 16 different taxes that accounts for over three (3) billion dollars
 annually, with a staff of over twenty-four employees.
- Completely changed and rebuilt existing processes in sixteen (16) taxes.
- Product Owner and Subject Matter Expert (SME) on multiple projects.
- Served as Ohio's expert witness regarding the Master Settlement Agreement.

Ohio Department of Taxation - Columbus, Ohio - July 2010 to May 2013

Tax Audit Manager Excise & Energy Tax Division

Contributions:

- Set individual employee and Division goals, as well as, established audit selection criteria that ensured the tax auditor agents completed over 200 International Fuel Tax Agreement audits and over 400 International Registration Plan audits annually.
- Assisted the Department of Taxation's Criminal Enforcement Division in analyzing data and calculating tax liability for criminal cases.

Ohio Department of Taxation - Columbus, Ohio - June 2009 to July 2010 Administrative Officer Excise & Energy Tax Division

Contributions:

- Administered the guidelines established by the International Fuel Tax Agreement.
- Created and maintained databases for the Division as a result of enacted legislation.
- Streamlined archaic processes that resulted in an increase in efficiency and productivity.

EDUCATION

Columbia Southern University - Orange Beach, Alabama - June 2010 to October 2011 Master of Business Administration

California University of Pennsylvania - California, Pennsylvania - June 2007 to June 2008 Master of Science in Exercise Science & Health Promotion

Muskingum College (University) - New Concord, Ohio - August 2000 to December 2002 Bachelor of Arts in Accounting & Business (Magna Cum Laude)

+References available upon request